TAYLOR BLATCHFORD

Phone: (720) 334-6737 // Email: blatchfordtaylor@gmail.com // taylorblatchford.com

Journalism Experience

Beat Writer and Copy Editor, The Maneater (Student Newspaper) // Aug. 2014 – Present Write 1-3 stories per week for the University News section, covering campus breaking news Edit content for spelling, grammar, AP Style and organization for print and online editions

Speaker, JEA/NSPA National High School Journalism Conventions // Nov. 2014 – Present Present sessions on various aspects of journalism to groups of 150+ high school students Intern, Colorado Community Media // Dec. 2014 – Jan. 2015

Reported and wrote stories on community-related topics, including sports coverage of 15 high schools, to be published in local newspapers in the Denver metropolitan area

Editor-in-chief, VISTAjournalism (Mountain Vista High School) // Jan. 2011 – May 2014

Managed comprehensive journalism program with 50+ staff members

Gained experience in writing, design, photography, editing and digital media

Produced newsmagazine, yearbook, website and broadcast publications

Attended national conventions sponsored by JEA and NSPA and local workshops

Publication won awards including NSPA Newspaper Pacemaker and All-Colorado awards

Media Storytelling Skills

Advanced: Adobe InDesign, DSLR photography, Adobe Photoshop, Google Fusion Tables, social media (Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Storify, Tumblr), copy editing and journalistic writing **Basic:** CSS/HTML, web development, Adobe Illustrator, DSLR video and video editing

Education

University of Missouri – Columbia // Expected Graduation: December 2018

Bachelor of Journalism, anticipated emphasis in convergence journalism Dual major in secondary education

Awards and Recognitions

Walter Williams Journalism Scholar, University of Missouri (2014 – present)
National High School Journalist of the Year, Journalism Education Association (2014)
Colorado High School Journalist of the Year (2014)
National Merit Finalist & National AP Scholar (2014)

Work Experience

Camp Barnabas // May 2014 - Present

Managed a cabin of personal care assistants that were each paired with a person with special needs while participating in camp activities

Brain Highways // Aug. 2013 - May 2014

Led games and activities for groups of elementary-age children that further develop their brains; gave small group presentations to parents; assisted with small-business organization

Festive Cup Coffee // Dec. 2012 - March 2014

Prepared and served handcrafted coffee beverages to customers Sold retail items and assisted with inventory, organization and creating displays